Ravi Koyyana

Mobile: (+91) 9902579889

E-mail: koyyana.raavi@gmail.com

About:

10 yrs of design & analysis experience in Gas Turbine Combustion systems. Interested in addressing problems by following basic fundamentals using data (experimental/analytical) for validation. Looking for an opportunity to work for an organisation dealing with variety of technical challenges to resolve customer issues by providing effective solutions.

Competencies & Skills:

- Strong Fundamentals in mechanical design and durability of Gas Turbine Combustion System.
- Expertise to provide engineering solution for entire Product Life Cycle of the combustion component like design, development, testing, vendor qualification, manufacturing, fleet issue and repair.
- Expertise in Finite Element Static & transient thermal, static & transient structural, Nonlinear Elastic-plastic, creep, contact, modal, harmonic and Lifing analysis using ANSYS, UG & Hypermesh.
- Knowledge of Fracture mechanics for crack growth & damage tolerance assessment.
- Expertise in durability assessment of the gas turbine combustor parts like thermal, structural, Low cycle fatigue, high cycle fatigue, fracture, oxidation and creep.
- Good at hand calculation for mechanical design and heat transfer.
- Worked on supplier qualification, data review and recommendations.
- Understanding of manufacturing drawing, tolerance stack up, GD&T and Bill of material.
- Knowledge of sig sigma design tools and concept for robust design.
- Always looks for opportunities of implementing quality, Continuous improvement & simplification.
- Leadership and team management. Planning, leading and executing deliverables.
- Strategy, Planning and Execution of direct material productivity/Cost Out.
- Strong analytical skill. Innovative mindset to address technical challenges.
- Excellent communication skills with the ability to relate to people at any level of business.
- Strong Documentation Skills. Own technical reviews from conceptual to validated design.
- Mentoring and coaching of Young engineers.

Professional experience:

Current Organization: General Electric (GE), JFWTC, Bangalore, India

Senior Engineer (April 2015 – Till Date) Lead Engineer (April 2012 – March 2015) Engineer (Aug 2008 – March 2012)

Educational Qualifications:

Course	Discipline	College/University	Year of Passing	Aggregate/Division
M.Tech	Mechanical (Solid Mechanics & Design)	IIT Kanpur, India	2008	8.25/10
B.E	Mechanical	NIT Raipur, India	2006	78/100

Computer Knowledge and FEA Skills:

FEA Package - ANSYS, HYPERMESH, UG Mesh Generation - ANSYS, HYPERMESH, UG

Modeling Package - UG

Post Processor - ANSYS, PropLife (In-house GE code for crack propagation)

Miscellaneous - MATLAB, ANSYS APDL

Rewards & Recognition:

- ERD (Highest level award for project) for 6B DLN1+ DF design & development
- Several Management awards & Global DMP of the month award for cost out.
- Several Project of the month/quarter award for project executions.
- Several team level awards for behavioural differentiator during project execution.
- 1 Patent
- TISCAT publication (GE Internal technical paper)
- GATE All India Rank 32
- Batch Topper in B.E.

Summary of Overall Professional:

Global ownership for Gas turbine Combustion component design and analysis:

- Engineering execution on Design, Manufacturing and Field issues pertaining to Gas Turbines Combustion Components.
- It involves providing engineering solutions during all the stages of product life cycle of Gas
 Turbine Combustion Components through analytical assessments. The responsibility includes:
 Design & Development of new products, Supplier Deviation's, Manufacturing Nonconformance, and Fleet Issues (reliability issues of hardware). Working very closely on abovesaid areas with design team, Material Engineer, Supplier Quality Engineer, Advance
 Manufacturing Engineer, Fleet Support and Product Service Engineer.

Next generation combustion system design and durability assessment:

- New product development program to cater to higher power & efficiency. Increased firing temperatures pose a significant durability & heat transfer challenges.
- Leading the entire effort of durability assessment for LCF and HCF in the context of completely new design and immature manufacturing process.
- FEA assessment, like thermal structural, modal and harmonic to estimate the LCF/HCF capability and subsequently design improvement.
- Develop a full scale analytical model to capture overall system response to mitigate the uncertainty of different loads & suggested design improvement ideas.
- Work with the cross functional team like manufacturing and MPE for estimating risk associated with inherent flaw and surface roughness based on fracture mechanics approach.
- Test & learn to prove initial design concepts and improve the existing capabilities.

Premix oil technology for low emissions & enhanced durability:

- The existing legacy diffusion technology is limited by emission regulation using water over a limited operations range in regions deprived of water availability. This program required the elimination of water usage and coming up with a novel product.
- Led the durability efforts for design and development right from conceptual stage. This involved coming up with a design that caters to inherent failures due to liquid oil operation. Few such failure modes are internal coking, external coking, high temperature metal fatigue.
- In the absence of completely understood flow/CFD models, developed empirical models using test data to map out the operational space which helped in reducing the test points by 3 times.

Mission based lifing for F-class combustion system:

- In order to avoid forced/un-planned outage's, the idea of remaining useful life based on the way the machine is operated was conceptualised. Enormous real time data was sought for developing physics based hybrid models.
- Employed innovative design process of applying the methods of data analytics, tribal knowledge, field data, and physics based modelling into a package that drives more revenue for GE combustors. Worked closely with services teams to come up with design methodology and implemented it for field validation on the fielded units.

E class 32K new product induction to GE Gas Turbine product portfolio

- Worked on design and development of E class 32K product development for GE Gas Turbine to eliminate completely the existing 24Khr combustion inspection interval and directly aligned with hot gas path
- Durability assessment of new design for wear, creep, oxidation, TBC spallation and bolt relaxation by FEA approach using ANSYS.
- Validation through lab test. Drive instrumentation requirements for lab test and data analysis for design validation.

Cost out, quality, simplification

- Challenge the existing design practice limitations and improved the modelling practices on several instances.
- Implemented several Kaizen ideas leading to 2-fold productivity enhancement.
- Explored and created opportunities for material productivity savings.

Certification and Training (Manufacturing/Shop Floor/ Power Plant/Other Trainings):

- Green Belt Certification for Design for Six Sigma (DFSS)/DMAIC.
- Leadership development training, Crotonville
- Trainings Fundamentals for Technologists, Building Essential Leadership Skills, Foundation of Leadership
- Shop floor, Supplier visits, power plant (DHABOL) visits to enhance manufacturing, assembly process for a gas turbine.
- BGGTS (BHEL and GE Gas Turbine Service/Refurbishment Shop) for enhancing repair knowledge for GT components.